Maaz Bin Salman

Lahore District, Punjab, Pakistan



maaz.salman08@gmail.com



+92 324 4196075



linkedin.com/in/maazbinsalman

Summary

Tech Enthusiast | People Oriented | Drive for results | Eager to learn & contribute to my environment

I am currently working in the Data Analytics department at CureMD. I have spent the last 4 years completing my bachelors in Electrical Engineering from a top tier engineering school in Pakistan. Area of expertise include core engineering subjects such as Power Analysis, Communications system along with computer oriented domains including programming (C++, Python, SQL) & Data Visualization tools (Power BI, Tableau).

I have found an acute appreciation of Data Analytics and the impact it generates for a company and the world we live in. I have completed projects using Python, SQL, Power BI, C#, ASP.NET, JS . I have also completed related certifications from Google, IBM, LinkedIn Learning and International Universities on Coursera.

Personally, I enjoy meeting new people and hearing new perspectives.

Experience



Associate Software Engineer

CureMD

Feb 2023 - Present (2 months)

- -Research and Implementation for multiple domains including eCQM, MIPS, UDS, Izenda and Data Analytics in CureMD to maximize client satisfaction. using SQL, Analytical Tools and Other Software
- -Finding potential reasons and applying fixes for all problems arising related to my domain for a smooth client experience and minimizing backlogs.



Software Trainee Engineer

CureMD

Aug 2022 - Feb 2023 (7 months)

- -Self Learning, Research and Implementation of Various Technology Stacks including Microsoft SQL Server, Power BI, Tableau, Izenda to help client achieve ultimate satisfaction.
- -Research and Implementation of software workflows to minimize time of resolution of issues.
- -Identification of possible reasons and fixation of bugs for a smooth transition of client to the latest software version.
- -Code Review, Merging and Deployment of latest changes by collaborating with multiple teams for product certifications.



Electrical Engineering Intern

Pak Elektron Limited

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 (2 months)

Design and implementation of commercial transformer (400 KVA)

Supply Chain Management Intern

PepsiCo

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

Analysing & improve SC process for Key Customers for PepsiCo to achieve efficiency gains (presentation to CEO Pepsi Co)

- 1. First Position among approx. 100 teams
- 2. Proposal include WH Shelf Tagging, use of barcodes in logistics to provide visibility in transit & introduce coherent systems between Pepci Co and its distributors to provide real time inventory situation

Data Analytics Intern

Quantium

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020 (3 months)

Customer Analytics through Data Preparation, Data Wrangling and visualisation.

Education



Ghulam Ishaq Khan Institute of Engineering Sciences and Technology

Bachelor of Science - BS, Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2018 - 2022

Licenses & Certifications

- Introduction to Programming Using Python IBM
- Supply Chain Principles Coursera
- in SQL Essential Training LinkedIn
- Advanced SQL for Query Tuning and Performance Optimization LinkedIn
- in SQL: Data Reporting and Analysis (2019) LinkedIn
- in Advanced SQL for Data Scientists LinkedIn
- SQL Tips and Tricks for Data Science LinkedIn
- in Tableau Essential Training LinkedIn

- in Business Intelligence for Consultants LinkedIn
- Learning Google Data Studio for Marketers LinkedIn
- Career Essentials in Data Analysis by Microsoft and LinkedIn Microsoft
- **G Google Data Analytics** Google

Skills

Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Entrepreneurship • Project Management • Microsoft Excel • Python (Programming Language) • Public Speaking • Microsoft PowerPoint • SQL • Data Analysis • Data Reporting